barriers and enhancers of communication so
some of the barriers distorted perceptions
distrusted sources transmission errors
noise anything noises anything that
interrupts a message message isn't clearly
encoded meaning the sender didn't make the
message clear enough or from the get-go
saying it's a bad idea.
Hostility, being emotional, those are all
barriers.
Culture, different ages, different
backgrounds, different religions,
different languages can all be barriers.
So that's why again, it's
so important for us to figure
out how we can all communicate
effectively with each other.
That is a big deal.
All right.
And power games, politics can definitely
be barriers.
Stop the communications.
Whereas enhancers, active listening,
again, nodding, repeating back what they
say in a question, not just totally
mimicking.
All right, make the message relevant to
the receiver.
reduce the message to simplest terms
organize the message into a series of
stages if at all possible repeat key
points make the messages timely but you
just don't send out information just to
send it out so you send out relevant
information in a timely manner and again
make the messages concise and clear,
anything that will help that communication
back and forth especially.